I don’t ever want to talk about being a woman scientist again.
我再也不想谈论身为女科学家这件事了。
There was a time in my life when people asked constantly for stories about what it’s like to work in a field dominated by men.
我人生中曾有一段时间，人们总是请我讲些故事，讲讲在男性主导的领域工作是什么感受。
I was never very good at telling those stories because truthfully I never found them interesting.
我从来都不太会讲这些故事，因为说实话，我从来不觉得它们有意思。
What I do find interesting is the origin of the universe, the shape of space-time and the nature of black holes.
我真正感兴趣的，是宇宙的起源、时空的形态和黑洞的本质。
At 19, when I began studying astrophysics, it did not bother me in the least to be the only woman in the classroom.
19岁开始学天体物理时，作为教室里唯一的女生，我一点也不在意。
But while earning my Ph.D. at MIT and then as a post-doctor doing space research, the issue started to bother me.
但在麻省理工学院读博士期间，以及后来做太空研究的博士后时，这个问题开始困扰我。
My every achievement—jobs, research papers, awards—was viewed through the lens of gender politics.
我的每一项成就——工作、研究论文、奖项——都被放在性别政治的视角下审视。
So were my failures.
我的失败也是如此。
Sometimes, when I was pushed into an argument on left brain versus right brain, or nature versus nurture, I would instantly fight fiercely on my behalf and all womankind.
有时，当我被卷入关于左脑与右脑、先天与后天的争论时，我会立刻为自己、也为全体女性激烈地争辩。
Then one day a few years ago, out of my mouth came a sentence that would eventually become my reply to any and all provocations: I don’t talk about that anymore.
后来，几年前的一天，我脱口说出了一句话，这句话最终成了我对一切挑衅的回答：我不再谈论那个话题了。
It took me 10 years to get back the confidence I had at 19 and to realize that I didn’t want to deal with gender issues.
我花了10年时间，才找回19岁时的那份自信，并意识到自己不想去应付性别问题。
Why should curing sexism be yet another terrible burden on every female scientist?
为什么消除性别歧视要成为每一位女科学家的又一个沉重负担？
After all, I don’t study sociology or political theory.
毕竟，我研究的又不是社会学或政治理论。
Today I research and teach at Barnard, a women’s college in New York City.
如今，我在纽约市的一所女子学院——巴纳德学院做研究并授课。
Recently, someone asked me how many of the 45 students in my class were women.
最近，有人问我班上45名学生中有多少是女生。
You cannot imagine my satisfaction at being able to answer, 45.
你想象不到，我能回答“45名”时有多满足。
I know some of my students worry how they will manage their scientific research and a desire for children.
我知道，我的一些学生担心将来如何兼顾科研和想要孩子的愿望。
And I don’t dismiss those concerns.
我并不轻视这些顾虑。
Still, I don’t tell them “war” stories.
不过，我不会给她们讲那些“战斗”故事。
Instead, I have given them this: the visual of their physics professor heavily pregnant doing physics experiments.
相反，我给了她们这样一个画面：她们的物理教授挺着大肚子做物理实验。
And in turn they have given me the image of 45 women driven by a love of science.
反过来，她们也给了我这样一幅图景：45名女性因热爱科学而奋进。
And that’s a sight worth talking about.
这才是值得一谈的景象。